# Kevin O'Neill

Ridgefield Park, NJ 07660 kevponce194@gmail.com 2014067735

I am a highly trained and experienced Prepress technician currently out of work due to COVID-19. I have been a working Manager of both Offset and Wide-format disciplines. Quite simply; I solve supplied file problems and accurately get them to press. I also have a degree in Graphic Design and have the ability to create files from scratch as needed.

#readytowork

## Work Experience

#### **Digital Dept Manager**

Vernon Display Graphics - Carlstadt, NJ August 2007 to Present

- Departmental (Working) Manager in charge of all aspects of preparing customer files for press as well as supervising a team of 4 Prepress Operators, 4 Pressman, 3 Finishers and 2 Router Operators.
- Highly skilled in Adobe Creative Suite applications, including retouching and color correction.
- RIP platforms include, but not limited to, EFI XF, Wasatch, Onyx.
- Responsible for ordering printing substrates, laminations, rigid board substrates and all ink.
- Responsible for calibration of presses, and for ensuring equipment operation and maintenance through supervision and protocols/procedures as well as contact with equipment vendors as repairs and PM's are required.
- Responsible for movement of jobs through department to ensure deadlines.
- Dept equipment includes: One EFI/Vutek 5R (5meter roll to roll). Two EFI/Vutek 3250's (3meter hybrids). One Screen Trupress (Flatbed). Two Esko-Kongsberg Routers. Two Seal Laminators. Two Fotoba XY Cutters.
- Over the years investigated and implemented new equipment installations as new technologies emerged increasing quality, productivity and turn-around.
- Client list includes: Vehicle Wraps for Mercedes-Benz, Hertz, HERC, Goya. 2D and 3D displays for various liquor accounts including Jameson, Malibu, Tito's, Hendricks, Absolut and countless other brands. Acrylic displays for multiple Cosmetics companies such as MAC, Bobby Brown, Estee Lauder, Ulta, Shiseido and Sephora. High-profile, color and quality critical imaging for Metropolitan Museum of Art and Christie's. POP 2D and 3D, window and in-store imaging for JCREW, Ann Taylor, Madewell and

Michael Kors. Pressure sensitive adhesive murals, and rigid board graphics for over 200 nationwide new and/or renovated stores for Dick's Sporting Goods.

### **Offset Prepress Dept Manager**

FLM GRAPHICS - Fairfield, NJ December 1996 to August 2007

- Prepress Dept Manager for Offset Printing Company responsible for preparing customer files for 4 Heidelberg 40" presses as well as Heidelberg DI (direct to press 13 x 19 format).
- Supervised a team of prepress operators, strippers and platemakers. Over the course of my employment the nature of offset prepress technology changed greatly from goldenrod and film to direct to plate so the personnel employed at any given time changed rapidly.
- Integral member of the management team responsible for implementing direct to imposed film, and later direct to plate.
- RIP platforms include, but not limited to Creo Prinergy, Linotype, DaVinci, Agfa as well as PREPS Imposition SoftWare.
- FLM was a mutli-disciplined company including 4 divisions: Offset, Wide Format, Reprographics, and Web Development/Asset Management. As Prepress Manager I was involved with, and often directly responsible for jobs and tasks within those divisions, and for a significant time held the dual responsibility of both offset and wide-format Prepress Manager.
- Of note; I was a member of the Board of Directors of the Heidelberg Digital Imaging Association as FLM was one of the first US locations for the revolutionary Heidelberg DI.

#### Education

### **Bachelor's in Communication Design**

Kutztown University of Pennsylvania - Kutztown, PA September 1980 to May 1984

#### Skills

- Adobe Creative Suite
- · Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- Creo
- · Graphic Design
- Prepress
- Microsoft Office Suite
- Adobe InDesign
- Web Design